{"tossups": [{"question": "During this campaign, Evans Carlson led a namesake patrol with just sixteen combat casualties in its pursuit of a force retreating from Koli Point. New Georgia Sound was known as \u201cThe Slot\u201d during this campaign for its role in the route of a certain \u201cExpress.\u201d A strategic airbase was captured by Allied forces during this campaign and renamed Henderson Field. The USS<em> Chicago</em> was sunk in this campaign\u2019s Operation<em> Ke</em> [KAY] evacuation. For the point, name this first major land campaign of the Pacific Theater of World War Two, fought in the Solomon Islands.", "answer": "<b> Guadalcanal</b> Campaign (accept Battle of<b> Guadalcanal</b>, accept Operation<b> Watchtower</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A revolt in this region led to a compromise to end a blockade in Italy, the Pact of Misenum. Naval fighting in this region\u2019s revolt included the use of the harpax at the Battle of Naulochus, where Marcus Agrippa defeated Sextus Pompey. Lepidus was exiled to Circeii by Octavian after an apparent conspiracy to take this region. An ally of Rome from this region was Hiero II, who may have asked Archimedes to verify if a crown was made of gold. Much of the fighting in the First Punic War took place near, for the point, what home island of the Kingdom of Syracuse?", "answer": "<b> Sicily</b> (accept<b> Sicilia</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "A loyalist from this dynasty captured Taiwan after this dynasty fell and was known by the honorific <em>Koxinga</em>. During this dynasty, the Zhengtong Emperor was captured during the Tumu Crisis and later abdicated in favor of the Jingtai Emperor. Zhu Yuanzhang brought this dynasty to power after the Battle of Lake Poyang during the Red Turban Rebellion. The Forbidden City was built by this dynasty which also sent voyages to Africa under the admiral Zheng He [ZHUNG HUH]. For the point, name this dynasty that fell to the Manchu invaders who established the Qing.", "answer": "Great<b> Ming</b> dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Another man with this surname represented Pennsylvania at the 1787 Constitutional Convention. For the point, give this surname of the \u201cFinancier of the Revolution,\u201d Robert, and the author of the Preamble, Gouverneur.", "answer": "<b> Morris</b> (accept Robert<b> Morris</b>, Jr. or Gouverneur<b> Morris</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A work by this author details Helmut von Moltke the Elder\u2019s affinity for reading Victorian romance novels before heading into battle. Another work by this author examines the events of the \u201ccalamitous 14th century\u201d through the lens of Enguerrand VII de Coucy. This author was present during the historic 1914 pursuit of the SMS<em> Goeben</em>, detailed in the \u201cBattle\u201d section of one of her books. This author won a Pulitzer for her biography of Joseph Stilwell, though she is better known for her book on the July Crisis. For the point, name this author of<em> The Guns of August</em>.", "answer": "Barbara W(ertheim)<b> Tuchman</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This leader addressed the possibility of \u201carmed battles\u201d in his Gazimestan Speech, given as part of his \u201canti-bureaucratic revolution.\u201d After strikes at the Kolubara mines against this leader, Ljubisav Doki\u00b4c [LYU-bih-sahv DOE-kitch] charged a wheel loader into the RTS building in the \u201cBulldozer Revolution.\u201dIn \u201cOperation Allied Force,\u201d this leader\u2019s country was bombed by NATO during a war with the KLA. This man died of heart failure in 2006 in the midst of a trial at The Hague. For the point, name this Serbian president of Yugoslavia during the Kosovo War.", "answer": "Slobodan<b> Milosevi\u00b4c</b> [sloh-BOH-dahn mill-OSH-eh-vitch]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s father led a crowd of armed men in protesting Guillaume Sayer\u2019s imprisonment at the Assiniboia Courthouse. This man\u2019s associate, William Bernard Donoghue, led raids in support of this man and lobbied for this man\u2019s cause to the American government. This man was finally captured after being defeated at the Battle of Batoche. The Wolseley Expedition was sent after this man after he personally executed Thomas Scott. For the point, name this leader of the Northwest and Red River Rebellions, a hero of the M\u00b4etis in Manitoba.", "answer": "Louis<b> Riel</b> (or Louis David<b> Riel</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This mercurial leader ordered a regiment to march to Siberia but changed his mind after they had walked ten miles. This ruler commissioned Vincenzo Brenna to construct St. Michael\u2019s Castle, where this man was killed in an assassination plot masterminded by Ludwig von der Pahlen. After Napoleon captured Malta, the Knights Hospitaller chose this ruler as their Grand Master. This ruler was reportedly the son of his mother\u2019s lover, Sergei Saltykov, despite his official father being Peter III. For the point, name this Russian tsar, the heir of Catherine the Great.", "answer": "<b> Paul</b> I (accept<b> Pavel</b> I Petrovich)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Prime Minister Hubert Pierlot forced that monarch out after this country\u2019s \u201cRoyal Question\u201d crisis. L\u00b4eon Degrelle led a group of fascist collaborators in this country with his Rexist Party. This country\u2019s King Baudouin acceded to the throne in, for the point, what country ruled by his father, Leopold III?", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Belgium</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "An act co-sponsored by this New Yorker was first fully applied in<em> New Negro Alliance v. Sanitary</em> <em>Grocery Company</em>. This man, who led the talk show<em> Talk to the People</em>, worked with Thomas Dewey to\u201cdrive the bums out of town\u201d and collaborated with Robert Moses to build such projects as the Brooklyn Battery tunnel. While in Congress, this man worked with George Norris to co-sponsor an act that banned yellow-dog contracts. For the point, name this Italian-American New Dealer who became mayor of New York City in 1934 and names an airport in Queens.", "answer": "Fiorello<b> La Guardia</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A semi-mythical ruler of this city was killed by Melanthus during a battle in Attica. Xanthos ruled this city, as did Pentheus, who was ripped apart by the daughters of this city\u2019s founder, Cadmus, after denying the divinity of Dionysus. Cadmus created this city\u2019s first inhabitants by sowing the teeth of a dragon. Heracles was believed to have been born in this city, the setting of the third play in Aeschylus\u2019s trilogy, the<em> Oedipodea</em>. For the point, name this ancient Greek city that was attacked by Polynices\u2019s army of Argives which was captained by \u201cThe Seven.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Thebes</b>, Greece", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "In 1905, this man met with Teddy Roosevelt to discuss U.S. participation in independence efforts. This man later obtained a PhD from Princeton and established the Han-in Christian Church in Hawaii. At the age of 75, this man was issued a passport by the U.S. military and returned to his nation of birth on board Douglas MacArthur\u2019s personal aircraft. An avowed anti-communist, this man led his nation during the Jeju Island uprising. For the point, name this man who resigned after the 1960 April Revolution, the first president of South Korea.", "answer": "Syngman [SOONG-MON]<b> Rhee</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A treaty that set the boundaries of this region used vague language like \u201cthe middle of the said channel,\u201d which led to the Pig War. A dispute over this region created the slogan \u201c54 - 40 or Fight!\u201d For the point, what is this region that names a certain westward \u201cTrail\u201d?", "answer": "<b> Oregon</b> Territory", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This painting\u2019s left side features a running man with a hand in his hat and a captured fleur-de-lis to symbolize victory. This painting depicts Simon Fraser behind a green-uniformed man pointing backwards, but Fraser was not actually at the historical event depicted. A squatting Native American with his chin on his fist stares at the main subject of this painting, who lies in a Christ-like pose surrounded by fellow British staff officers. For the point, name this Benjamin West painting that depicts the fate of a commander at the Battle of Quebec.", "answer": "<em> The<b> Death of General Wolfe</b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This organization replaced the Jesuits in developing what would become Saint-Laurent-du-Maroni, part of a system that included the Salvation Islands. Until 1947, this organization administered French Guiana as a penal colony, in part because it didn\u2019t have jurisdiction over Algeria. Like other<em> for\u00b8cats</em>, Jean Valjean in<em> Les Mis\u00b4erables</em> was sentenced to hard labor in a<em> bagne</em>, one of many prisons administered by this organization in cities like Rochefort, Toulon, and Brest. For the point, name this branch of a certain nation\u2019s military which shackled convicts in the galleys of Louis XIV\u2019s fleet.", "answer": "<b> French Navy</b> (accept<b> Navy</b> of<b> France</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The grand opening of this city\u2019s harbor was interrupted by Francis De Groot of the New Guard, who cut the red ribbon with a sabre. One rebellion in this city ended when colonial forces intervened at Rouse Hill. This city was the site of a rebellion dubbed the Second Battle of Vinegar Hill, fought by convicts on Castle Hill. William Bligh was ousted from power in this city during the Rum Rebellion. The HMS <em>Endeavour</em> made landing at Botany Bay, a few miles south of this city. For the point, name this former penal colony, the largest city in Australia.", "answer": "<b> Sydney</b>, Australia", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In 1922, riots in this city occurred after men continued to weave Panama hats past September 15th. Peter J. Brennan\u2019s support of President Nixon led to riots in this city in which a postal worker raised a U.S. Flag in City Hall. Riots in this city occurred when AFL-CIO members attacked protesters of the Kent State shootings in the Hard Hat Riot. Another riot in this city was quelled by Union troops pulled from the Battle of Gettysburg, a riot that burned down the Colored Orphan Asylum. For the point, name this city that faced the 1863 draft riots.", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City, New York (accept<b> NYC</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of these items was worn by Fess Parker in a television series by Disney. This object, which was initially worn while debating E.H. Crump, became the trademark of Estes Kefauver. Benjamin Franklin wore one of these things while negotiating with France to play on stereotypes of American frontiersmen. A craze for these items in the 1950s was caused by a television series about the \u201cKing of the Wild Frontier.\u201dFor the point, name this kind of headgear associated with Davy Crockett, fashioned from the fur of a nocturnal mammal.", "answer": "<b> Coonskin cap</b>s (accept anything related to a<b> hat</b> made out of a rac<b>coon</b>) Page 6", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This case\u2019s decision was limited in<em> Bethel v. Fraser</em>, and it concerned an action meant to support Robert Kennedy\u2019s proposed \u201cChristmas Truce.\u201d<em> Morse v. Frederick</em> ruled that a sign reading\u201cBONG HITS 4 JESUS\u201d failed to pass this case\u2019s \u201csubstantial disruption\u201d test. For the point, name this Supreme Court case which ruled that students\u2019 freedom of speech allowed them to wear black armbands to protest the Vietnam War in Iowa.", "answer": "<em><b> Tinker</b> v. Des Moines Independent Community School District</em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One member of this party, Gulzarilal Nanda, was acting prime minister of his country for thirteen days on two separate occasions. The first occasion was after the death of a member of this party who gave the \u201cTryst with destiny\u201d speech and coined the term \u201cNon-alignment movement.\u201d Another prime minister from this party declared a state of emergency which allowed for \u201cRule by decree.\u201d That prime minister in this party approved the \u201cSmiling Buddha\u201d nuclear test. For the point, name this party of Indira Gandhi and Jawaharlal Nehru.", "answer": "Indian National<b> Congress</b> (accept<b> Congress</b> Party, accept<b> INC</b>))", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This town\u2019s first marshal, Fred White, is buried near Billy Clanton in this town\u2019s Boot Hill. This town\u2019s best-known event occurred in an empty lot on Fremont Street during a Wednesday in 1881. For the point, name this town in southeastern Arizona, once protected by U.S. Marshal Virgil Earp, the site of the Shootout at the O.K. Corral?", "answer": "<b> Tombstone</b>, Arizona", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This event\u2019s central figure was cheered for helping the fallen Lord Rolle. The \u201cHallelujah Chorus\u201dwas played during this event in place of a planned piece by the recently deceased Thomas Attwood. This event was the first to use the Gold State Coach in place of a foot procession after leaving Buckingham Palace. The lack of rehearsal prior to this event concerned Benjamin Disraeli, but this event\u2019s central participant went on to be the second-longest reigning monarch in English history. Westminster Abbey hosted, for the point, what 1838 crowning ceremony?", "answer": "<b> Coronation</b> of Queen<b> Victoria</b> (accept descriptions of<b> Victoria</b> being<b> crown</b>ed before\u201ccrowning\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The losing side in this battle planned a frontal attack whose failure was blamed on Alexander Cochrane. Thomas Mullins forgot to bring ladders to cross the Rodriguez Canal at this battle whose winning side was aided by a group of Choctaw and the Baratarians of Jean Lafitte. The losing commander, Edward Pakenham, was killed, but the Americans suffered only 62 casualties at this battle. Taking place eighteen days after the Treaty of Ghent was signed, for the point, name this battle of the War of 1812 that bolstered the reputation of Andrew Jackson.", "answer": "Battle of<b> New Orleans</b> Page 7", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Prior to this historical event, one character tries to motivate a group with a rousing speech accusing one man of being \u201cA bloody tyrant and a homicide\u201d and ends by appealing to \u201cGod and Saint George!\u201d The loser of this event earlier killed his brother, Clarence, and imprisoned the sons of Edward IV in the Tower of London. During this event, that character yells, \u201cA horse! a horse! my kingdom for a horse!\u201d his final words before being killed. Henry Tudor won this battle, bringing an end to the House of York. For the point, name this battle that occurs at the end of Shakespeare\u2019s<em> Richard III</em>.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Bosworth Field</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}